So the first step in trimming any piece is to make sure that it's centered.
And the way that you do that is start the wheel head spinning, and you're going to see that it's a little off center right now.
So, it's a process that takes a little while to learn.
It's called tapping on the center.
But you really just pat the pot, give it a little spank.
It's kind of counter intuitive, because you're hitting, at first you're going to want to hit at the wrong place and you're going to make it more off center.
Give yourself some patience with that.
Once you've got it on center, you're going to take your ribbon tool.
This is called a ribbon tool because when you go to trimming, it makes a ribbon of clay that peels right off of the piece.
So I just want on the outside part, to make it smooth.
It doesn't need to be changed in shape very much.
But on the inner piece, you can see there's a little corner, a little ledge, and I don't want that to be there.
So I'm going to remove that with my ribbon tool as well.
So once that's smooth, the next thing you do is you smooth the bottom of the piece out with your sponge.
This is going to be the last time you're going to touch the bottom of it before you fire it, so make sure it's to your satisfaction.
And now is the time when you would either sign in your name, or push in your impression with a stamp that you've either made yourself and fired, or a rubber stamp that you've had made at a rubber stamp company.
Push that in there, and we're ready to do the trimming on the bowl.